<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data science on jmtirado.net</title>
    <link>https://jmtirado.net/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data science on jmtirado.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2023 Juan M. Tirado</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 09:10:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmtirado.net/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The many challenges of graph processing</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/the-many-challenges-of-graph-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 09:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/the-many-challenges-of-graph-processing/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I exposed my opinion about the lack of a clear platform/solution/framework/architecture for graph processing. However, what are the main issues graph processing has to deal with? Serve these lines as an appetizer for the curious minds out there.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph processing: a problem with no clear victor</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/graph-processing-a-problem-with-no-clear-victor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 09:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/graph-processing-a-problem-with-no-clear-victor/</guid>
      <description>We all depend on the Internet to search for potential solutions to technical problems. For example, for big data problems after five minutes in Google you will find out that Spark may help you.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can Borges teach you about overfitting?</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/what-can-borges-teach-you-about-overfitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 15:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/what-can-borges-teach-you-about-overfitting/</guid>
      <description>Jorge Luis Borges (1899-1986) was a brilliant writter and one of the most influential authors of all times. His tales are a must-read for anyone interested in science/science-fiction. But what can Borges teach you about overfitting?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid19 spreading in a networking model (part II)</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-spreading-in-a-networking-model-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-spreading-in-a-networking-model-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>The original Jupyter notebook can be found here.
Introduction # This notebook is the second part of our analysis of how air traffic may have contributed to spread the Covid19 virus.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid19 spreading in a networking model (part I)</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-spreading-in-a-networking-model-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 11:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-spreading-in-a-networking-model-part-i/</guid>
      <description>This is a reproduction of a Jupyter notebook you can find here
Introduction # The Covid19 has imposed a lot of pressure on epidemiologists to come up with models that can explain the impact of pandemics.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 forecasting</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/covid-19-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/covid-19-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Introduction # This is the third part of our series about Covid19 data analysis. This series is inspired after the proposed Kaggle challenge. This notebook introduces some practical examples of univariate time series forecasting.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 interactive plots</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/covid-19-interactive-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 17:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/covid-19-interactive-plots/</guid>
      <description>This is the continuation of my series about how to manipulate Covid-19 data with Python (first entry here). This post adds some extra complexity and introduces some interesting options to define interactive plots.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 visualization</title>
      <link>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 18:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmtirado.net/covid19-visualization/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of a series of publications describing solutions used in data science. The content is self-explained in a Jupyter Notebook available at my Github account. This first post explains different ways to display time series using Python with Pandas for data management, and Matplotlib or Seaborn for data visualization.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
